HUYNH DUY KHANG – FLUTTER ENGINEER

Address: Go Vap, Ho Chi Minh - Phone: (+84) 762449965

Email: huynhduykhang2001gv@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/khang-huynh-15b0b1248/

Github: https://github.com/DuyKhangIT

SUMMARY

I am a Mobile Engineer with 3 years of experience (Specifically: Flutter).

Drawing on extensive experience in application development and software performance optimization, I consistently stay updated with the latest technologies and continuously enhance my skills.

My ability to work efficiently under pressure and solve problems swiftly enables me to deliver high-quality results on time.

Motivated by a commitment to sustainable growth and continuous improvement, I am confident in my capacity to create significant value for the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Dart, Java, Kotlin

Frameworks/Platforms:

❖ Flutter

❖ Design Patterns (MVP, MVC, MVVM), OOP (SOLID), State management (Clean Architecture, GetX, Provider, Bloc), Restful API,...

Database Management Systems: SQL Server, MongoDB, MySQL

Local Database: SQLite, Hive, Floor...

Orders: Google map API, Socket IO, Firebase, Pipeline (GitLab CI/CD), Flutter version management (FVM)

Tools: Jira, Bitbuckler, Open Project, Github, GitLab, Postman, Appcenter, Testflight, Slack, Lark, Rocket Chat, Figma, Draw.io,...

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ECR Company - Flutter Developer

2/2024 - Now

 Project: Rail Pro – ECR Project (14 members: 3 font-end, 5 back-end, 3 tester, 3 mobile)

• Description:

- o Application for purchasing and managing goods on trains for customers
- Online and offline payment for cards, cash
- o Runs on a Pax device

Technologies:

- o Mobile: Flutter, Java, Kotlin
- Database: SQL Server, Postgresql
- o Back-end: C# .Net
- o Front-end: Angular, JavaScript
- Others: FVM, Firebase, Retrofit,...
- o Design patterns: OOP (SOLID), MVVM, State management (Provider, GetX)

• Responsibilities:

- ➤ Handle Sync Data from server to local database of device (Hive, Floor)
- > Implement Lazy loading of Product list
- ➤ Build a feature to send Emails and SMS after completing a transaction
- ➤ Retrofit API configured with timeout settings
- ➤ Build the **End of Day** functionality to summarize sold products, transactions, and other data, then push it to the server
- ➤ Implement **Session management**: Create a session on app start, store it locally, and end it at the end of the day
- > Build the **Login** function
- ➤ Handle **Tracking orders** (Update delivery status)

- ➤ Handle **Manual sync data** (Process the success or failure of each called API and calculate the percentage of data that has been synced)
- ➤ Handle **QR scanning** for automatic departure selection
- Fix bugs and implement new features

Other duties:

- > Build and deploy App on Testflight
- > Support UI design for applications with Designer
- > Support manual testing with QC
- > Support testing API with BE
- Meeting and discussing with Teams
- Project: IMPL (8 members: 2 font-end, 3 back-end, 2 tester, 1 mobile)

• Description:

 Application used to manage business activities of a shipping company in Singapore (ERP).

• Technologies:

o Mobile: Flutter, Kotlin

Database: SQL Server, Postgresql

o Back-end: C# .Net

Front-end: Angular

o Others: FVM, Firebase, Retrofit, Flutter MethodChannel,...

o Design patterns: OOP (SOLID), State management (Bloc, GetX)

• Responsibilities:

- > Implement Lazy loading for list
- ➤ Build **Operation** module
- > Build OCR feature (Scan the package label and extract text into the input field)
- ➤ Build **Multiple languages** support for Vietnamese, Singaporean, and Indonesian
- ➤ Handle **upload file**, **camera** (Flutter MethodChannel + Kotlin code)
- ➤ Handle permission for each android versions (Flutter MethodChannel + Kotlin code)
- > Developing and optimizing the image upload compression function

- > Setup Sentry tool (monitoring and error detection)
- ➤ Build Light/Dark mode function
- > Developing the **Permits** function
- > Responsive UI
- ➤ Handle **Local notification** to remind clock-in/out
- ➤ Handle **Firebase notifications** to receive messages from the server
- ➤ Handle **Silent notifications** (Firebase Cloud Messaging)
- Fix bugs and implement new features

Other duties:

- ➤ Build and deploy App on **Testflight**
- Support UI design for applications with Designer
- Support manual testing with QC
- Support testing API with BE
- ➤ Meeting and discussing with Teams and Customer

EcarAid Company (eCa app) - Flutter Developer

6/2022 - 1/2024

- Project: Eca App (6 members: 1 font-end, 2 back-end, 1 tester, 2 mobile)
- Link:
 - o CH Play: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ecaraid.eca&hl=vi
 - o App Store: https://apps.apple.com/vn/app/eca/id1613176058?l=vi

• Description:

 The eCA application is designed to effectively manage vehicles, supporting many conveniences for car owners

• Technologies:

o Front-end: Flutter

o Database: SQL Server

o Back-end: Java spring boot

o Others: Firebase

o Design patterns: State management (Clean Architecture)

• Responsibilities:

➤ Build **Register** fuction

- ➤ Detected nearby problems feature, displaying customized icons on maps for each Gagares, place autocomplete (Google API), filter icons on maps, polylines (Google API)
- > GPT chat integration
- ➤ Handle Firebase notification when the user receives a voucher
- ➤ Build **Booking** feature (Repairing cars, roadside assistance, vehicle maintenance, etc)
- > Chat group feature (handle sending media, document file, location and booking request) and notification to chat room,
- Build Car used trading and Service package feature
- ➤ Handle upload files, photos
- > Developing video playback from YouTube links
- > Developing **Xims online** feature
- > Build a Car club membership feature,
- > Share **QR** code with social media
- Fix bugs and implement new features

Other duties:

- Build and deploy app on AppCenter
- Support UI design for applications with Designer
- > Support manual testing with QC
- > Support testing API with BE
- > Daily meeting

EDUCATION

Ho Chi Minh City University of Foreign Languages and Information Technology (Vietnam) 08/2019 - 08/2023

> Studying: Software Engineering

Degree grade: GPA 8.0

SOFT SKILLS

- > Teamwork
- > Resolved issue

- > Presentation
- > Creative thinking

CERTIFICATES

- ➤ Bachelor's degree in information technology (Good)
- > TOEIC 505